Of all the games in my collection,
在我收藏的所有游戏中
few raise my excitement level at the mere sight of it like this one.
很少有游戏能像这个勾我的魂儿
Doom II: Hell on Earth,
Doom II: Hell on Earth（毁灭战士二：地狱上凡）
developed by id Software and released to North American retail
由id Software开发，在北美
by GT Interactive Software on October 10th, 1994.
由GT Interactive Software在1994.10.10发行
Exactly ten months after the shareware release of the original Doom, which was still wildly
他们正好在原版《毁灭战士》发行十个月后趁热打铁
profitable despite only being sold via phone or mail order.
就算原版《毁灭战士》仅仅通过电话或邮件订货就能收益颇丰
And that’s one reason Doom II happened so quickly
而这也就算为什么《毁灭战士二代》能这么快就能发行
publisher GT Interactive really wanted a copy of Doom to sell
发行商GT Interactive十分希望在1994年假期档
by the 1994 holiday season.
赶紧发行个《毁灭战士》续集
They’d worked with id Software already, having distributed these registered full versions
他们在之前已经和id Software合作过了，而且已经发行过了
of Commander Keen: Goodbye Galaxy and Wolfenstein 3D.
完整版Commander Keen: Goodbye Galaxy和《德军总部3D》
But Doom was another beast entirely, able to rake in $100,000 worth of orders a day
但是《毁灭战士二代》又是一个热门，在零售还没开始的情况下
without any retail presence whatsoever.
一天就预售了十万美元！
To put it bluntly, id Software didn’t need a publisher for Doom.
id Software不想找发行商发行，因为他们像直接获利
GT was adamant though, and after a couple of meetings that went nowhere,
然而GT坚持发行，所以在几次小黑屋py交易之后
an agreement was reached.
他们达成了协议
Doom II would be developed with a $2 million marketing budget, and id Software would retain
《毁灭战士二代》的宣传将会有两百万的预算，而且
all intellectual property rights, creative control, and company branding on the front
开发商将会拥有软件的所有权，艺术品所有权
of the box instead of the back.
而且必须在包装盒的正面，而不是背面，打上开发公司标志
Another part of this deal was that, unlike the original,
协议中还有一点，不像原版《毁灭战士》那样
Doom II would not get a shareware version at all.
《毁灭战士二代》没有免费版本
Developer John Carmack for one seemed fine with this, stating that “A lot of people
开发者之一John Carmack对这个十分满意，他说：
很多人把免费版本的《毁灭战士》打完后
就认为他们已经“把毁灭战士通关了”
《毁灭战士二代》将完全是商业产品
so they’d left the shareware model behind this time.
所以他们这次没有想过发行免费版游戏
And well that worked out, considering Doom II was the best-selling game of 1994.
然后他们想的没错，《毁灭战士二代》是1994年的畅销游戏
Demand was so high that its initial print run of 600,000 copies sold out in a single
这个游戏过于畅销，以至于一天之内首批六十万份游戏
month, with total copies sold surpassing 1.5 million by the end of the ‘90s.
便抢购一空，整个九十年代更是卖了创纪录的150万份
And it was this original US release that I first saw around Christmas of ‘94, proudly
我在94年圣诞假期时就看见了美首版，就在当地K-Mart的
displayed on a front endcap in the PC gaming section at a local K-Mart.
电脑游戏区最前面的摆台前熠熠生辉
It stood out for a variety of reasons, not the least of which was its box art, painted
它在众多游戏前脱颖而出的原因是多样的，不仅是它鲜艳的
by acclaimed fantasy artist Gerald Brom.
封面，由盛名远扬的幻想派画家Gerald Brom绘制
That gruesome cyberdemon with its weird exposed abdomen, Doomguy wielding his shotgun and
吓人的Cyberdemon展示着它恐怖的暴露腹部，而Doomguy挥舞着
that utterly bonkers haircut, smashing cinder blocks with his butt.
他的猎枪和狗啃的发型，一屁股就把下面的煤渣给坐碎了
And of course it stood out because dude, it was Doom, Part Two!
当然，这还不足以抓人眼球，这可是《毁灭战士》啊！还是二代啊！
Something I had no idea existed until I saw it on the shelf for $50,
一开始我没反映过来，直到我看见它卖50美元
with the original game nowhere in sight.
而且原版《毁灭战士》也没有找到:-（
Kinda strange in retrospect, but before Ultimate Doom came around in 1995, the only version
现在想起来还是觉得奇怪，但是在1995年《终极毁灭战士》上市前
of Doom for sale in stores was Doom II, and maybe Doom I shareware.
市面上你能买到的只有《毁灭战士二代》，也许还有原版《毁灭战士》
A fact that seemed to cause some confusion if these newspaper ads are any indication,
实际上当时报纸上打的广告由于搞错封面，造成了许多误会
check out this mixup by Staples. Whoops.
看看Staples报纸上打的广告吧:-P
Doom II was also the first time I’d seen this new thing called an ESRB rating, this
《毁灭战士二代》也是我看见的的第一个有ESRB评级的游戏
imposing black and white ‘M’ on the box.
盒子上有这个醒目的黑白的M标志
注：年龄限制：17岁及以上
Yep, this hit shortly after the big video game ratings debate in the US, and Doom II
是的，这个就在席卷美国全国的电子游戏讨论之后发行
注：咱们啥时候游戏也能这样分级，玩游戏本身不会导致青少年不学好
was one of the first to earn itself a Mature rating.
而这个游戏也是第一个获得M级（成人级）的游戏
Something not seen on the UK release distributed by Virgin Software,
而英版游戏，由维珍游戏发行，在包装方面有所缩水
Recommed Virgin Record Music:
Ommadawn - Mike Oldfield
Phaedra - Tangerine Dream
Nevermind the Bullocks Here's the Sex Pistols
lending this particular cover a cleaner overall look.
让包装看上去更加平实
Then again, it doesn’t have that shiny, embossed cardboard that the American one has, so eh.
这个再一次地，没有像美版那样，有抛光和浮雕，所以呢
You win some you lose some in the worldwide Doom II box art department.
各地的《毁灭战士》包装都互有优劣:-|
Anyway, enough persnickety packaging ponderment!
无论如何，包装大家也看腻了，
Inside the box you get Doom II itself on either a CD-ROM or a quintet of 3.5” high density
盒子里面装的就是《毁灭战士二代》游戏了，不是装在CD上
floppy disks, with each format sold as its own SKU.
就是装在软盘上，每种包装都是不同的条码
There’s also this 8-page manual addendum booklet with plenty of DOS-related setup tips
这里还有八页的附加手册，上面有DOS相关的安装提示
and frequently asked troubleshooting questions.
和一些疑难解答
And then there’s the Doom II instruction manual, with 14 full-color pages of backstory,
然后就是14页全彩的游戏手册，包括背景故事
gameplay tips, and listings for each weapon, item, and enemy in the game.
游戏贴士，和游戏中所遇到的武器，物品和敌人介绍
Fantastic stuff, but I’m beyond ready to play now so let’s get to it!
东西很好，但是我欲火焚身，所以咱来一局吧:-D
Doom II for DOS starts off the same as its predecessor: a vivid 256-color splash screen
DOS版《毁灭战士》启动后，和前代一样，仍是生动的256色图片
with depictions of demonic destruction and some overly ominous music.
上面描绘着恶魔毁灭世界的场景，伴随着不祥的音乐
That's just the Sound Blaster version.
这个只是声霸卡合成版
It also supports the Roland Sound Canvas and other MIDI devices of course,
当然，这个还支持Roland Sound Canvas和其他的MIDI合成设备
but there’s something about the combo of Doom
但是《毁灭战士》游戏和
and Bobby Prince’s creepy OPL3 music
Bobby Prince编的吓人OPL3音乐
that makes me the happiest.
让我金属的内心受到了滋润
From here you can start a new game by selecting your difficulty, and... that’s it!
在这里你可以开局新游戏，然后选个难度......然后就享受吧！
No episodes to choose from this time, instead it’s a continuous 30-level campaign.
这回咱不用选章节了，你要一口气打连续的30个关卡
Straight away the action begins, with a pistol in your hand and zombies in your sights.
开局相当直接，手里有把枪，准备打僵尸
Or you could take the opportunity to look around and soak in the environment, which
或者你可以花点时间，看看周围，探索环境
inevitably brings your attention to this spot over to the left hiding the chainsaw.
很快你就会发现后面的过道右面藏着个电锯
Yeah I pretty much always go chainsaw.
是的，我是电锯的忠实拥趸
If you’re paying attention, by the end of level one you’ll have a pistol, a chainsaw,
如果你足够细心电话，第一关通关时，你会有一个电锯
a shotgun, a rocket launcher, a bunch of armor, and full health.
一把猎枪，一个火箭发射器，一些护甲，还有满血
Armed to the teeth after the very first level, that’s the Doom II experience right there.
第一关你就武装到了牙齿，那下面的关卡自然不在话下啦
You’re prepped for the upcoming slaughter right off the bat, with Doomguy boasting speed,
你已经准备好开始你的地狱受虐之旅，Doomguy快速又敏捷地奔跑
agility, and overall control that remains as satisfying as it was in the original Doom.
而且玩这个游戏的手感和原版《毁灭战士》简直是一模一样
No surprise since Doom II is built on the same tech and pretty much acts as a standalone
谁让《毁灭战士二代》和前代用的技术是一样的呢？而且这个基本上
expansion pack to the original game.
就是原版游戏的扩充包呢
It has the same 2.5D id Tech 1 engine running underneath, the same technical limitations
它的底层同样使用2.5D id Tech 1 游戏引擎，而且同样地
in terms of not being able to look up or down or have rooms over rooms.
不能上下看，或者屋子和屋子相连
There’s no jumping, no vertical aiming,
没有跳跃，没有垂直瞄准
no special moves to pull off or skill trees to unlock.
没有什么特殊方式跳关或者解锁能力树啥的
And that’s all awesome in my book.
而这些在我而言，都是非常不错的
Shoot demons, find key cards, unlock doors and secret rooms, find more key cards, reach
杀掉敌人，找到钥匙，解锁秘密之处，然后找更多的钥匙
the exit and move onto the next level to do it all again until you reach the end boss.
来解锁开关，进入下一关卡，如此下去，直到看见最终BOSS
Well-balanced FPS goodness, so why fix what ain’t broke?
既然FPS已经发展的那么好了，那这还能发展什么呢？
Because unbroken things can always be fixed with more guns, I guess.
我猜，他们可以设计更多的枪来解决
This was made in Texas, after all.
毕竟这个游戏是在德州开发的，对吧
注：来自德州的神奇科技 BV1Dz4y1Q7ba@David Murray & Woodear
Yeah it’s time we talk about Doom II’s big fat arsenal: truly one of the great joys in life.
现在我要给大家展示《毁灭战士》的超强军械库了，绝对让您爱不释手
Beyond the aforementioned fist, chainsaw, pistol, shotgun, and rocket launcher, also
抛去上回说到的锯子，手枪，猎枪和火箭发射器以外
making a triumphant return is the chaingun, with its rapid fire room-clearing abilities
还有最好用的常胜将军机关枪，能够快速扫荡整个屋子
proving as useful as ever against enemies near and far.
无论近战还是远战，都是得力助手
There’s also the plasma gun, frantically firing energy cells as quickly as the original
当然，这里还有等离子枪，打出等离子的速度和原版一样
Doom, but popping up far earlier this time, on the fifth map.
但是出现的时间比之前更早，就在第五个地图上
And of course, it isn’t Doom without the BFG, and again you can find it faster this
当然，没有BFG的《毁灭战士》是称不上《毁灭战士》的
time, with level eight and onward becoming your personal playground
但是这回它的出现时间更早了，在第八关拿到后
of glowing green plasmic destruction.
你就可以开始你的等离子屠杀计划啦:-D
And then, ohh-ho-ho, and then.
然后......等会！还有！
We’ve got the one and only, the often imitated but never duplicated,
还有那个一直被模仿，从未被超越的
double-barreled Super Shotgun.
双管超级猎枪
Introduced near the beginning of level two, this monster of a weapon
你在第二关就会发现，然后当你用过这个怪兽般的武器后
is pure triple-filtered bliss.
你就会感受到刘备得到诸葛亮时如鱼得水的快乐了
Sure it takes twice the ammunition as the regular shotty, but it’s more than twenty
虽然它比单管猎枪要多用双倍的子弹，但是这可是
times as satisfying so the trade off is a no-brainer.
比单管枪多了不知多少倍的快乐啊！那这交易不就值了吗:-)
Just two metal barrels held together with a piece of wood and explosives in the middle,
仅仅是把两个枪管用一个木枪托合在一处，再装点弹药
it undersells itself on aesthetics and completely over-delivers on power.
也许长了张猴子脸，但是一棒子就能能结果了你
More often than not, a single well-positioned shot is all it takes, and that’s for the
往往都是由它来打出致命一击，而这就够了
majority of the enemies in the entire campaign.
打战役的时候，这就是常态
It’s little wonder why it’s called the Super Shotgun,
这也就是为什么这个叫：超级猎枪
because that’s just what it is!
因为它可是耐人啊！
Though I suppose technically it’s the combat shotgun,
尽管我认为实际上这个应该称为：战斗猎枪
going by the included documentation, but
至少在手册中是这样写的，但是
Eh that term brings to mind a whole ‘nother category of semi-autos and self-loaders, so
额，这至少让我想到一堆半自动枪和全自动枪
I’m glad they gave this side-by-side a more appropriately super name in the actual game.
所以我在游戏中看到更合适的“超级猎枪”名字，感觉更加亲切
And what good is a big bad new weapon without a big bad new lineup of satanic minions
还有一点，超强的新武器那一定得有更厉害的妖魔鬼怪
to shoot in the face?
来展示出它的魅力啊
Doom’s original ten monsters were pretty great, and they’re all still around, including
原版《毁灭战士》的十个怪兽当然还在这里腻味你们
creatures like the Cyberdemon that used to be bosses but now just show up to ruin your
包括你很熟悉的Cyberdemon，原版是Boss，现在
注：DOOM永恒称为暴君
day throughout the whole game.
它在这里专门腻味你，阻止你通关
But Doom II rounds out the enemy roster by doubling down on demons, and as a result it
但是《毁灭战士二代》还特意添加更多敌人来进一步恶心你
really feels like the whole gang’s here now.
让你觉得敌人团结起来，更加强大
The Heavy Weapon Dude wields a chaingun and can absolutely wreck your life if you’re
重机枪僵尸装备了机关枪，当你疏忽的时候
not careful, that hit-scanning is no joke.
他们分分钟就能让你去当太虚幻境的门卫，他们的连击武器可不认人的
Hell Knights are like weaker, tanner versions of the old barons of hell, nothing terribly
地狱骑士就像是恐惧骑士的缩水版
threatening so I welcome the target practice.
没啥可怕的，你就当他们在插标卖首就好啦:-)
The Mancubus is a big old blob of terror with dual flamethrowers and a whole lotta hitpoints,
生化肥球如名所示，可以一次射出两大火球，立马将你搞死
slow but effectively nasty.
虽然很慢，但是很腻味人
Arachnotrons are versions of the old spider demon, this time much smaller and shooting
蜘蛛怪是上代机械蜘蛛的缩水版，这个更小而且
blasts of green energy, which are thankfully easily dodged.
可以射出绿色能量波，幸亏处理起来相当容易
And Pain Elementals, now these just suck, being another floating blob like the Cacodemon,
还有痛苦元素，本体就是鸡肋，就像是另一个漂浮怪兽巨脑魔
but spitting out lost souls instead of ball lightning.
但是这个不吐红色闪电，而是丧魂
Way more annoying due to that, what a pain...
所以这个解决起来很麻烦，真是个痛苦......
elemental.
元素:-(
Then you’ve got the Revenant, a tall lumbering skeleton beast
然后是骷髅兵，一个拥有硕大笨重骨架的打怪物
with shoulder-mounted rocket launchers and blood for pants.
肩膀上帮着火箭发射器，让所有前世伤害它的人血债血偿
Not too hard to kill, but its rockets are basically homing missiles, so there’s that.
消灭起来倒是容易，但是值得注意的是，他带的火箭发射器的伤害很大
And finally, there’s the big daddy chaos bastard of Doom II, the Arch-vile, which is
终于，这里还有个极其难缠的大家伙————召唤师
not only terrifying to look at, but deadly to look at as well.
不光看上去很可怕，而且看上去很致命:-(
Simply making line of sight contact with the thing can result in you being set on fire
仅仅是与他对视，你就会引火烧身
until you explode, which is not ideal.
直到你从地狱直升天堂，这可真是够恶心的
Arch-viles can also bring lower-tier enemies back from the dead if you let them stick around
如果战斗相持很久的话，它能将死去的敌人续上一命
long, so don’t do that.
所以见到它，一定要速战速决
Kill ‘em hard, kill ‘em fast.
刀起刀落间，就置其于死地
Oh yeah, and there’s a couple secret levels that include killable Commander Keens hung
当然，这里还有两个秘密关卡，包括可以杀掉的
注：德国版由于涉及纳粹标志，故没有包含
from the ceiling, and even SS troops from Wolfenstein 3D.
上吊的Commander Keens, 甚至还有《德军总部3D》的党卫军
注：《Commander Keen（指挥官基恩）》和《德军总部3D》均为id Software开发
But these are more like easter egg/in-joke kinda things, you won’t be seeing any keens
但这个更像是彩蛋之类的东西，你绝对不会在
or nazis wandering around the streets of Earth or the spaceports of Mars.
火星上的太空基地上看见指挥官和纳粹走狗
Speaking of which, another thing to touch on are the levels themselves, the atmosphere
说到这个，我还想谈论一下这个游戏总共30个关卡的设计，
they provide, and the overall pacing throughout the 30-level campaign.
氛围的设定，还有整个的节奏
Because, well, this is where Doom II is kind of a mixed bag in my opinion.
因为呢......《毁灭战士二代》要我说就像是水泊梁山
注：原意为这个游戏像锅大杂烩，虽然好玩，但是总有几处让你想不明白
Don’t get me wrong, it’s still a really well-made bag
不是通俗的意思，那些好汉都是遵纪守法的
filled with all sorts of fun goodies to play with.
找他们帮忙不仅和气相待，而且不会闹得官府想方设法招安
It’s just that inside the bag are a couple of questionable pockets filled with odd-shaped
只不过这些好汉里有几个长得很可疑
doohickies that you don’t quite know what to make of.
让你觉得他们有点黑
My biggest qualm is that around a quarter of the levels are rather unappealing to me,
我最大的疑惑是这个游戏大约四分之一的关卡不太吸引我
specifically the ones that are supposed to be based in our realm.
尤其是那些本应该基于我们日常生活的关卡
I mean, for a game titled Hell on Earth, I expected a lot more Earth, with like,
你看啊，这个副标题叫“地狱上凡”，好歹人间烟火得更多些吧
hell on it and stuff.
然后再穿插几个地狱关卡
Instead we’ve got a barely-connected selection of levels that are loosely sanctioned off
然而我们玩到的是互相衔接比较松散的几个关卡
into three episodes: The Space Station, The City, and Hell.
大致分为三个部分：太空基地，街头混战，地狱之战
Again, for the most part I have a lot of fun playing Doom II, over and over again.
再次强调，这个游戏的大多数关卡都十分有趣，我更是反复把玩的
Martian space stations and pixelated hellscapes, aw yeah, gimme more of that!
火星上的太空基地和像素化的地狱......小二，再上几关！
But then you’ve got levels like Downtown that just... what is this?
当你打到诸如市中心关（第十三关）时......这玩意是嘛？
Props for trying something new I guess,
也许我在尝试一些新的东西吧
a metropolitan area and skyscrapers in the Doom engine is kinda neat.
DOOM引擎里的大都市和摩天大楼画得倒是不错
But it’s a slog to navigate and there are far too many enemies right above your line of sight.
但是这也是战斗的号角，而且你满目之下，全是妖怪:-(
Then there are maps that largely exist to promote some level design gimmick, like Tricks
也有些地图专门画得很大来炫耀他们精巧的设计，诸如
and Traps, The Chasm, and Barrels o’ Fun.
捉迷藏（第八关），鸿沟（第二十四关）和油桶连环炸（第二十三关）
Stuff like monster infighting, teleporter logic, tricky platforms, skinny walkways,
诸如怪兽窝里斗，传送带神用途，恶心的平台，极细的过道
hundreds of explosive barrels strung together, it’s like being stuck in a lab experiment.
好几百个油桶放一块，我们不是卡在了张飞虐兵实验所了吧？
Maps like these are bizarre, sorely sticking out from the rest.
这样的关卡十分怪异，从头到尾都很难
I don’t wanna call out any particular level designer here (Sandy Petersen)
在这我就不让设计这些关卡的人拉出来公开处刑了(Sandy Petersen)
Sandy: 海绵宝宝，我找你找的好苦啊！来，咱们到针堆里找松树叶吧:-)
but the more I’ve played these maps over the years, the more I dread enduring them again.
但是我这几年来越是仔细把玩，越是听见就害怕
That's not to say all the new map styles fall flat, though.
当然，这也不是说这些新地图都是平庸之作
There’s a lot more experimentation than Doom 1 with enemy quantity and wide-open spaces,
这些关卡比初版《毁灭战士》更具实验性，怪兽们在开阔的场地里聚集
enabling these ridiculous battles with dozens of demons attacking, screaming, dying, and
从而有一些超级扯淡的关卡，你会在和怪兽周旋时看见他们互相攻击
in-fighting while you circle strafe around picking them off, I love this stuff.
哀嚎不止，以至于混乱中内斗，咱们就等着渔翁得利吧:-)
A side effect of these larger, densely-packed levels is that the performance suffered on
而这些又大又复杂的关卡的一大副作用就是
lower-end machines back in ‘94, leading to higher system requirements for Doom II
在发行时的1994年，低端电脑的表现不佳，进而
compared to the original.
对《毁灭战士二代》的系统要求就更高了
What better reason to grab a 486 Overdrive though, right?
所以咱必须装个486 Overdrive，对吧
注：BV1XE411M7dw 更换一块83MHz的奔腾OverDrive CPU @ LGR & 某科学的小姚同志
Some levels also play with darkness to an excessive degree, making for one fittingly
有些地方黑暗的角度十分怪异，从而营造出一种合适的
foreboding atmosphere, and granting greater justification for the existence
恐怖气氛，从而让夜视镜的存在
of the Light Amplification Visor.
变得更加合理
However, the creep factor is somewhat lessened by your amped-up firepower, not to mention
然而，这个并不会让你的增强火力变得更加厉害
the new Megasphere that boosts your health and armor to 200%.
更不用说新加的可以将护甲和生命都加到200%的超次元球
It’s dark, sure, but not to the point of unfairness.
当然，环境确实很黑，但还没让你觉得不公平
Anyway yeah, even though the occasional map design makes me scratch my head in bewilderment,
无论如何，尽管经常遇见的地图难题很让人抓狂
the overall Doom II experience is one that I cherish.
但是我玩《毁灭战士二代》时的体验还是令我珍惜的
And I freely admit that the super shotgun silliness has a lot to do with it,
而且我确实认为超级猎枪确实能立大功
as arguably overpowered as it is.
即使它功力确实被夸大了
But it’s just too enjoyable for me to care!
但是我还是十分喜欢用的！
Maybe it’s another story dealing with it in multiplayer deathmatch, but the main draw
也许咱改天再提多人死亡生存模式吧
for me is the single player so I’m all for it.
因为咱今天主要提的是单人游戏，那咱就光说这个吧
Then you add in the expanded bestiary of baddies and huge retail presence, and it makes sense
然后你就买到了更多的怪兽和更多的火力
that Doom II took off in a way that even its predecessor never did.
难怪《毁灭战士二代》比一代的影响力更大
And I’m talking strictly in terms of community engagement, not like, sheer quantity of installations
显然，我要说的是社区的活跃度，而不是说大量的安装量
or overall cultural relevance.
或者说整体的文化氛围
Obviously Doom 1 has its place in history, but Doom II is the one that formed such strong
显然原版《毁灭战士》在历史上有着浓厚一笔，但是
community bonds that remain active to this day.
《毁灭战士二代》的浓厚文化圈子到现在还很活跃
The sheer number of custom maps and total conversion WADs made for it is staggering,
数量众多的自制地图和WAD在现在看来仍然是很惊人的
both back then and into the present.
无论是在当时还是在现在
And the proliferation of them has only increased since the source code was released in 1997,
而在《毁灭战士》的引擎在1997年开源以后，对游戏的定制就更多了
resulting in source ports and fan-made upgrades like GLDoom, ZDoom, Boom, Chocolate Doom,
然后就有了GLDoom，ZDoom，Boom，Chocolate Doom
Skulltag, Zandronum, and beyond.
Skulltag, Zandronum之类的改进引擎
I’m currently quite fond of Crispy Doom in particular, for when I want to play on
当我需要在现代电脑而不是古董机上打游戏时，我十分喜欢用
a modern machine instead of original hardware, and find myself wanting a few extra quality
Crispy Doom，因为这个可以在不破坏
of life improvements without ruining the original feel of the game.
原版游戏体验的情况下提升了性能和功能
And then there was the retail side of things, with Doom II expansions and addons hitting
再提销售方面，在1994年《毁灭战士二代》发行后
shelves for years after its 1994 launch.
各种针对其的插件和扩展就一直充斥着市场
The first official one being Master Levels for Doom II in 1995, consisting of 20 WADs
而官方也在1995年发行了《毁灭战士二代大师关卡》，包括
promising to be masterfully-made, and nearly three thousand fan-made maps
二十个游戏大师设计的关卡和多达三千个从网上下载的
downloaded from the fledgling internet.
由粉丝制作的关卡
Also has this rather radical poster expanding on the box art.
还有这个超大的海报，将盒子上画的东西给放大了
Then there was Final Doom in 1996, an officially licensed standalone product featuring two
然后就是1996年发行的《最后的毁灭战士》，一个官方授权产品
new episodes, TNT: Evilution and Plutonia Experiment,
包括两个新战役：TNT: Evilution 和 Plutonia Experiment
and which was in reality far from the actual final Doom.
当然，这和真正的结尾还差很远呢
Because next was the Depths of Doom Trilogy in 1997, packing Ultimate Doom, Doom II, and
因为1997年他们还发行了the Depths of Doom Trilogy
Master Levels into one beefy big box package.
大箱子里面包含一二代《毁灭战士》和《大师关卡》
There’s also been a slew of repackages and re-releases since then, with one of the more
当然，之后还有一大堆重新发行，其中最有意思的
interesting being Doom II to Xbox 360, which introduced No Rest For The Living, an all
是Xbox 360版，里面有No Rest For The Living，由
new expansion episode by Nerve Software.
Nerve Software制作的全新战役
It’s pretty good stuff actually, I recommend it!
说真的，这玩意还行，我十分推荐！
The episode has subsequently shown up in the Doom 3 BFG Edition, which itself includes
这个后来附加在《毁灭战士3》BFG版本里，当然里面也有
Doom II, and can also be played using a source port with the right WAD file.
《毁灭战士二代》，而且你也可以在有合适WAD的情况下，找个引擎玩
And that’s not to mention the whole unlicensed scene, with third-party publishers like WizardWorks
当然各种非授权产品就更多了，各种第三方公司，诸如WizardWorks
releasing at least half a dozen map compilations in their D!Zone series starting in 1995.
从1995年开始，已经发行了至少半打称为D!Zone系列的地图集
Doom II was its own gaming ecosystem throughout the mid-90s, with stuff sold in stores, distributed
《毁灭战士二代》在整个九十年代都有自己的游戏生态
online, shared among friends, and even created by the US government.
店里有买的，朋友间也会共享，甚至美国政府也插了一脚
Yeah, Marine Doom was a thing, an official project
是的，我说的就是Marine Doom，一个由
of the United States Marine Corps Modeling and Simulation Management Office.
美国海军陆战队建模仿真实验室开发的关卡
Hehe, ahh the 90s were wild man.
呵呵，九十年代真可是疯狂的年代:-P
And that, folks, is Doom II.
好了，老哥儿，这就是《毁灭战士二代》啦
As far as projects go that were slapped together in less than a year, instigated by the financial
这个游戏虽然是在见钱眼开的发行商催的情况下
incentives of a hungry retail publisher?
在少于一年的工期内赶出来的
Yeah, it could’ve sucked, but thankfully id Software did what they did back then and
是的，也许这个游戏会很差，但是在当时，id Software已经
made something excellent on their terms.
尽力做了，而且在满足条件的情况下，还更上一层楼
The way I see it, Doom II took what Doom did and ran with it, fleshing out the experience
据我看来，《毁灭战士二代》继承了原版的游戏结构之类
and cementing its reputation.
而且充实了游戏内容并扩大了名声
It’s hard to imagine the series without Revenants and Super Shotguns.
天知道要是没有骷髅兵和超级猎枪的话，这个游戏将会如何
Or shooting a giant wall demon that actually hides John Romero’s head on a stake.
或者射击一墙大的怪兽，实际上后面是立在木桩上的John Romero之头
And yet for a time, these were nowhere to be found, and reality was worse off for it.
而且在当时之后的一段时间内，这类游戏很难找到，而且搞到一份也是很值了
Doom II made Doom more Doom-like than ever before,
《毁灭战士二代》让毁灭战士更像毁灭战士了
and even with its flaws, I love it nonetheless.
虽白璧微瑕，我还是很喜欢
现在正在播放Bobby Prince的The Demon's Dead
本视频由SuperBart翻译，原作者LGR发布于2019-10-15
And if you liked this then perhaps check out my other Doom-related stuff right here.
如果你还想看更多《毁灭战士》视频的话，请看下面介绍
Or maybe even subscribe, I release new videos each week here on LGR.
或者B站搜索LGR，有好多人翻译我的视频呢
And as always, thank you very much for watching!
一如既往，感谢大家收看！